Preliminary guide to the Robert Sargent literary papers, 1923-2006 MS2308
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Robert Sargent literary papers
1923-2006
1950-2006
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Sargent, Robert
Barnett, Mary Jane
MS2308
11.5 Linear Feet 23 document boxes
Robert S. Sargent was an electrical engineer, Defense Department defensive weapons specialist, and published poet who lived most of his adult life in Washington, DC. He was born in New Orleans in 1912 and died in Washington, DC in 2006. He began writing poetry in his fifties. This collection includes published and unpublished poetry, drafts, correspondence, and biographical materials related to the literary and personal life of poet Robert Sargent. The materials range in date from 1923-2006.
Scope and Contents
This collection includes published and unpublished poetry, drafts, correspondence, and biographical materials related to the literary and personal life of poet Robert Sargent. The materials range in date from 1923-2006.
Biographical / Historical
Robert S. Sargent was an electrical engineer, Defense Department defensive weapons specialist, and published poet who lived most of his adult life in Washington, DC. He was born in New Orleans in 1912, raised in Mississippi, and was a 1933 graduate of Mississippi State University. After serving in the Navy during World War II, he worked at the Pentagon from the late 1940s until 1972. During his time at the Pentagon he was the recipient of the Distinguished Civilian Service Award.
Sargent began writing poetry in his fifties and published 11 books of poetry: Now is Always the Miraculous Time (1977), A Woman from Memphis (1979), Aspects of a Southern Story (1983), Fish Galore (1989), The Cartographer (1994), Stealthy Days (1998), The Jazz Poems of Robert Sargent (2000), Altered in the Telling (2001),Wonderous News (2002), 99 After 80 (2003), and Lula and I (2004). Sargent's literary subjects included his family, the South, art, love, the Bible, and jazz. His poems were published in a number of literary journals, including Antioch Review, New York Quarterly, Georgia Review, Poetry Review, Prairie Schooner, Western Humanities Review and many others. His poems also appeared in a number of anthologies, including Poetry magazine's The Poetry Anthology.
Sargent died on April 24, 2006 in Washington after suffering a stroke.
Arrangement
Organized into three series: Biographical documents; Correspondence; Poetry
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Mary Jane Barnett, August 31, 2012, 2012.072
Poetry; Poetry -- 20th century; Barnett, Mary Jane
- Biographical documents, 1923-1998; Series 1
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains documents from Sargent's childhood, materials relating to his career as an engineer, an essay written by Sargent on special relativity, a travel notebook, and certificates from the Department of Defense. The materials range in date from 1923-1998.
  - Early Personal Materials, Circa 1923-1950; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Life as an Engineer [1/2], Circa 1942-1985; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Life as an Engineer [2/2], Circa 1942-1985; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Paper on Special Relativity, Circa 1950-1998; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Travel, Circa 1986-1997; Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Standard Electrical Distribution Construction Details, 1943 January; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Department of Defense Certificates, 1972; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - VHS Tapes, Undated; Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 1933-2005; Series 2
  Arranged alphabetically. Some folders appear to be out of alphabetical order. When this is the case it was as the donor intended.
  This series contains personal correspondence between Robert Sargent and his family, friends, fellow poets, musicians, and others. Of note is a letter Sargent wrote to Albert Einstein and Einstein's reply. The materials in this series range in date from 1933 - 2005.
  - Correspondence, Art, Circa 1977-1984; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence with Sir Isaiah Berlin (philosopher), Undated; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence with Sidney Chilton (best friends), 1958-1977; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence with Sidney Chilton, 1933-1974; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence Sidney Chilton, 1976-1982; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence Sidney Chilton, 1970-1975; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence with Freeman Dyson (physicist), 1981-1982; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Early Correspondence Misc, 1933-1970; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Early Correspondence with Albert Einstein, 1953-1987; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Early Correspondence with family, 1962-2001; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Early Correspondence with friends, 1979-2000; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence with Bob Gordon, 1994-2005; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence with Carlton Hull, 1973-1977; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence with Ben Guider, 1989-1991; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence with Josephine Jacobson, 1989-1995; Series 2 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence with Ciray Jacobik (poet), undated; Series 2 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence with Armin Landeck (NY Artist 1905-1984), 1949-1978; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence with Philp Larkin, 1985; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence with Riley Patterson, 1934-1985; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence with John Pauker Poet, 1991-1997; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence with Ritter, 1935-1953; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence with Rorty, Philosopher, 1988-1989; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Round robin- Various Subjects, 1974-1979; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence with Hilda Thorpe (artist), 1995-2000; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence with Various Authors, 1960-1980; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence with Reed Whittemore Poet (Poet Laureate), 1984-2004; Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - After Reading Same Poems by John Ashbery, undated; Series 3 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - An American Story, undated; Series 3 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Poetry, 1961-2006; Series 3
  Organized into four subseries: Poetry and other writings; Poetry reading supplements; Business records; and Published works.
  This series contains drafts and final copies of more than one hundred Robert Sargent's poems. It also contains records of and materials used for Sargent's public poetry readings and correspondence and records concering the publishing of Sargent's books. Finally, this series contains copies of poetry journals and anthologies in which Sargent's poetry is published. The materials in this series range in date from 1961-2006.
  - Poems and other writings, undated; Series 3 Subseries 1
    The original order of this subseries has been maintained. The poetry has been arranged alphabetically first, with the other writings arranged alphabetically at the end.
    This subseries contains drafts and final copies of over 100 of Robert Sargent's poems as well as essays and other unpublished poems.
    - 90 not Seventy, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - The Abandoned Road, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - After Hilda, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - After 60 Years, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - After The Meeting, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - American Flag, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - The Amorite Commander, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - The Animals, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Ann, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Another Love Poem, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Another Triumph, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - The Aphorism, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - An Apology to Ruskin, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - An Arrangement of Words, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - The Artist Portrays, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - The Artists, Aging, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - The Artist, Responding, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Aspects of a Southern Story, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - At the Breakfast Table, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - At the Childe Harold, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - At the Poetry Group, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Aunt Winifred, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - At the Edge of the city, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Aunt Winifred, Commenting, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Adjuration, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - After School, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - The Agnostics, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Art Cards, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Asheville, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Aunt Warsley, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - A Ballad For Annie, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Barking Dogs, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - The Bath Towel, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - Basie's How Long Blues, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - The Beasts of Pitt Street, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Behavior, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 37)
    - Being 90, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 38)
    - Behind the Paining, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 39)
    - Beltway On-line, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    - Ben Shahn, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 41)
    - Ben Webster, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 42)
    - Big Daddy Prime, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 43)
    - Billy Holiday, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 44)
    - A Birch in Winter, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 45)
    - Bix, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 46)
    - The Blood of the Lamb, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 47)
    - Blues, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 48)
    - Blues for Chu, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 49)
    - Bones, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 50)
    - Boswarth Field, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 51)
    - Bowl Game, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 52)
    - Botticelli's 1478 Venus, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 5, Folder 53)
    - The Brook Cherith, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - A Bus Passenger, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Butter Pat, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Changing World, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Coffee Shop, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Cold Deserted Streets, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Coming Down from Oxford, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - The Concept of Force, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Copley Square, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - The Critics, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Crossing Woodrow Wilson Bridge Bridge, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Crying, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - The Culprit, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Capitol Hill House, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - The Cartographer, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - The Cat, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Cato the elder, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - A Cause for Regret, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - A Cavafy Poem, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - A Cartain Day, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Certain Song's, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Chalking the Pavement, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - A Change in Views, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Christine, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - The Chronological Ordering of Art Cards, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Circe to Ulysses, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Civility, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Clinchmore, Tenn, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - The Cockroach, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Careful about Words, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Changing, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Charles IX, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Comforting Words, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Constantinople, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - The Curve Maker, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Dante, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - An Ending in Spain, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - The Exhibitionist, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - The Echo, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Eighteen & K NW, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - Eight Bottles of Beer, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - Eisenhower, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - Elisha and the Children, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - The Elusive Ovenbird, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - The Elms, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 45)
    - Empty Days, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 46)
    - English 406, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 47)
    - Epiphanies, Large and Small, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 48)
    - The Epistemologist, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 49)
    - Epithalamiom, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 50)
    - The Etruscan Sculpture, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 51)
    - Ezra's Pact, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 52)
    - Exegesis, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 6, Folder 53)
    - The Dancers, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - The Dancing Class, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - A Dark Night, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Darwin at Work, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - The Daughter, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Daumier Lithograph, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - The Dentist, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Dewey, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Dickens, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Did You Know Boon Hogganbeck, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - Dido, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Dissemination, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - The Divorce, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - The Dogs of Vicksburg, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - The Doewagger Queen, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Dream of the Speaking Wolf, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Dressing with Whitman, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Drinking, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Driving Along Wilson, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - The Drooler, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - The Dure at Work, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - D'ye Ken the Names of John Peel's Hounds, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Family Secrets, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - For a Teenager, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - Daddy, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Dot and Jack, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Family, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Father's Day Message, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - The Father of the Prodigal Son, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - Fate of a Poem, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Faulkner, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Feet on the Shelf, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Feynman, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Finding a Poem, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Fish Galore, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - For D.H. Lawrence, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - The Fortunate Woman, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - Forty Thousand Thousand Fathers, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - France, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - Fred Chappell, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - Frederick, Maryland, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - Freckles, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 40)
    - From "Hay" to "Hi" and from Supper to Dinner, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 41)
    - From Vicksburg to Madrid, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 42)
    - A Funeral at Clarksville, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 43)
    - Funeral Meditation, as a song, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 44)
    - A funny Happening, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 45)
    - Gallery Observations, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 46)
    - General Pickett, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 47)
    - Gentility, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 48)
    - George, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 49)
    - The Giraffe, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 50)
    - The Grandmother, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 51)
    - The Greek Muses, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 52)
    - Gregor Mendel, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 53)
    - Harry and I, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 54)
    - Hilah, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 55)
    - Gallery 35: The National, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 56)
    - The Game, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 57)
    - The Goat, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 58)
    - The General, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 59)
    - Geronimo, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 60)
    - A Glimpse of the Future, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 61)
    - The Gospel Writers, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 62)
    - A Great-Big-Green-Pickle!, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 63)
    - Grandfather to Grandchild, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 7, Folder 64)
    - A Grocery Store, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Growing Things, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Hannah, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - A Happening at Taos, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - The Happy Marriage of Leonidas, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - The Heads, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Henry Barry Sargent, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Helping Women, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Heraclitus, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Heralds Sad, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Herr Professor Gauss, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Hesitant Pauses, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - The Historian, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Hoagy, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - The Hot Water Jug, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - A Housewife, Dozing, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - How to find Christine in Summer, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - The Husband..., Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Hull and the Bard, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - The Humming of Tunes, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - The Identity of "They" in "They Flee Me", Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - If Ritter Were Here, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Innsbruck, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - In the Courtyard, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - In the Garden, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - In the Garden, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - The Invalid, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Invocation, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - In the Small Hours, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - In the Phantasmagonia, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - Jack the Ripper, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - John Quincy Adams, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - Judging a Portrait, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - Jacksonville, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - Jake Barnes, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - James P Johnson, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - Jane, At a Cocktail Party, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 36)
    - Janie, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 37)
    - Jericho's King Worrying, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 38)
    - Jesus and the Centurion, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 39)
    - Jesus as a Triangle, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 40)
    - Johnny Green Hill, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 41)
    - John Ruskin, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 42)
    - Joshua, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 43)
    - J-O-O-S, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 44)
    - Joyce's Voice, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 45)
    - July 1931, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 46)
    - Jazz Devotee, Young Women, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 47)
    - Ken, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 48)
    - Kwajalew, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 49)
    - Lady Grace and Lady Chris, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 50)
    - The Laggard Muse, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 51)
    - A Lament for Worthington Whittredge, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 52)
    - Landing at Sea, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 53)
    - Lasca, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 54)
    - The Last Letter, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 55)
    - Last Names, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 56)
    - The Last Supper, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 57)
    - Late-Life Recognition, Undated; Series 3 Subseries 1 (Box 8, Folder 58)